so let's see how we can implement the
log function our log function needs to
do something like this we need some sort
of a magical lock that works without
using locks that protects a critical
section in which we check if the lock
variable is zero we put one in the lock
variable and we leave because we have
just successfully acquired the lock if
the lock variable is one we repeat all
of this and we need to let others also
be checking so really we need to insert
the unlock magic here and here so
basically we're just trying to do this
check and if it's zero setting to one
atomically with each other using some
sort of magic obviously there is no
magic so if there is no magic what do we
do there are several ways to get the
effect that lock magic would give us one
way is to use what's called lamport's
bakery algorithm or some other algorithm
that actually is able to use normal load
and store instructions to replace lock
magic but these algorithms tend to be
relatively complicated and just a simple
log function would take tens of
instructions to do so doing this is
expensive it makes the log function slow
the other option is to use some sort of
special atomic read and write
instructions so there would be an
instruction that does this check and set
to one or something similar to that that
would allow us to in one instruction do
this without needing the magic